Guide to the Milly Itzhak Riot Grrrl Collection ca. 1992-1997 MSS.280
Fales Library and Special Collections
Milly Itzhak Riot Grrrl Collection
1993-1997
Fales Library and Special Collections
Itzhak, Milly
MSS.280
2.5 Linear Feet (3 boxes)
Milly Itzhak was actively involved in the local art, music, DIY and youth activism scenes in Florida and created and published several zines between 92-96. During this time she maintained correspondence with youth and feminist activists and zine writers around the United States. The Collection consists primarily of zines either created by Itzhak or sent to Itzhak in the early and mid 1990s. There is also a small amount of associated correspondence and other ephemera that was sent through the mail.
Provenance
Milly Itzhak donated her collection to NYU's Fales Library in 2010.
Scope and Content
The Milly Itzhak Collection Riot Grrrl Collection consists primarily of zines either created by Itzhak or sent to Itzhak in the early and mid 1990s. There is also a small amount of associated correspondence and other ephemera that was sent through the mail.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically. Correspondence and other ephemera that were originally inlcuded with zines have been kept together.
Biographical Note
Milly Itzhak attended high school in Miami, FL in the early 90's (1992-96) and was actively involved in the local art, music, DIY and youth activism scenes. She created and published several zines between 92-96, including Eat these Sandwiches, The Ruby Slippers, Physics for Modern Architects, and Wick (co written w/ Trina Sargalski). During this time she maintained correspondence with youth and feminist activists and zine writers around the United States. Itzhak currently lives in New York City, where she has worked as a Motion Picture Camera Assistant since 2000 (member IATSE Local 600). She graduated from New York University's Tisch School of the Arts with a BFA Film and Television in 1999. She received a Certificate in Graphic and Digital Design in 2011 from Parsons The New School for Design, and is currently transitioning to Graphic Design work.
Punk culture.; Correspondence; Posters.; Fanzines.; Feminism.; Printed ephemera.; Riot grrrl movement.
- Series I: Zines and Related Correspondence
  - The adventures of mirabella snagglefoot #2, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Alien, lucky number 7, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Babykins #9, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Babykins #10, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bowling Ball Trimnastics #1, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The Carrier/Coffeehous Sketches/Radio, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Carrot #2, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Character Generator #9, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Character Generator (C.G.) #10, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Cupsize #5, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Cutiepie #5, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Daffodil #11, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Daffodil #12, August 1996 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Daffodil #13, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Daffodil #14, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - The Dangers of Libel, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Death + Tortillas #4, May 1996 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Demirep #4, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Don't Even #8(Amerika on Trial)/Tainted #2, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Doris #6, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Drop Out #4, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Drop Out #5, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Eat These Sandwiches, 1993,1994 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Everything Tastes Better With Ketchup #11, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - FB (Feminist Baseball) #11, April 1993 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Forbidden Planet (y.m.a.w.l. #3.5), October 1996 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Good Faerie #12, December 1995 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Good Faerie #12 1/2, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Homocore N.Y.C. #4, September 1995 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Jumbo Shrimp #10, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - K.N.E.E.:Kids Network for Empowerment and Education #1, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Looks Yellow, Tastes Red(Looks Good, Tastes Bad) #9, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Looks Yellow, Tastes Red #11, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Manifixation #3, Summer 1996 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - The Mean Reds, December 1996 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Meat is Murder #6, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Mind Junk #3, November 1996 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Mind Junk #4, December 1996 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Moon Queen Screams #2, October 1996 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Muffin Bones #3, Summer 1996 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - No Duh #3, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Palm Trees and Paper Hearts, May 1996 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Pattycake, July 1996 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Peter Vile/Mr. Stubbles/Christian Man vs. The Atomic Pirates, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Princess Charming #2, January 1996 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Reality Control #7, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Rock Candy #4/Spirals Upward #3, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Rock Candy #5, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - The Ruby Slippers, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - The Ruby Slippers #2, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - You Might As Well Live #4/Superette #12, Fall 1996 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Samsara #1, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Samsara #2, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Scarbaby #1, August 1996 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - SideTracked #7, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - SideTracked #8, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - This is Not a Travel Journal, part 2, May 1996 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - The Variest, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - The Variest #2, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Various Correspondence, 1996, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Various Flyers, 1996, 1997, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Various Small Zines and Flyers, 1996, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Wick #0, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Wick #1, April 1993 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - YAWP!#12, January 1996 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - YAWP!#13, February 1996 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - YMAWL #6, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)